RESUME

SHYAM KUMAR

BE- (MECHANICAL ENGINEER)

POST:- Electro Mechanical Engineer(MEP)

Address: VILL-Narharpur, Near I.I.M Road Lucknow

Contact-9169484900, 8299298815

Gmail:-shyamkumarlko434@gmail.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE:

With a Bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering and 2 years' construction industry, Power Plant and building construction. I am conversant with piping and HVAC Fabrication, installation, Erection. Basic knowledge of electrical installation and drawing. To obtain a challenging position ina high quality engineering environment where my technical knowledge and academic skills will add value to organizational operations and where I can enhance my capabilities through academic experience.

QUALIFICATIONS:

- ▶ B.E (Mechanical Engineer) with Aggregate percentage 70.5%. From RR INSTITUE OF MODERN TECHNOLOGY LUCKNOW.(Affiliated to AKTU LKO.)
- ➤ 12th from COSMOPOLITON INTER COLLEGE LKO. IN 2014(UP BOARD) Aggregate Percentage 64.4%.
- ➤ 10TH From Dr. BERENDRA PRATAP SCHOOL LKO. IN 2012 (UP BOARD) Aggregate Percentage 67.83%.

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES

- > Develop construction specification and scope work documentation of the job.
- Reviewing shop drawing, co- ordination drawing and Isometric drawing.
- Responsible for all kinds of mechanical work, ie- Piping, Fire Fighting, systems and HVAC.
- Basi knowledge of Electrical Drawings and installation.
- Ensure work done according to approved drawings, method statement specification and Quality standards
- Preparing daily man power distributing report with daily work progress and weekly progress Reportforclient
- > Co- ordination with clients, consultant and sub-contractor.
- > Maintaining the site materials order and check requirements of materials according to site
- > Plan and schedule as per project management department to proper flow of work.
- > Co- ordination with other disciplines to ensure clearance is available to start work.
- Inspection, Testing and Commissioning of all the system related to fire fighting and HVAC.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- ➤ One year experience in the designation of HVAC ENGINEER for a period of 01-nov-2018 to 15-oct-2019.In SEMINFRATECH PVT LTD LUCKNOEW.
- ➤ Join CLIMATISATION PVT LTD NEW DELHI. For a period of 25-oct-2019 TO 25-DEC-2019. As HVAC SITE ENGINEER.
 - I have worked at New Tech Pvt Ltd as a MEP (**Electro Mechanical Engineer**) for a period of July 2020 to Feb 2023

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES

- ➤ Get approved HVAC Shop Drawings, MEP- Coordination Drawings, Work method statement and Project Specification from Project Manager.
- Ensure the HVAC Ducts, Fittings, accessories and Child water pipes, fittings, accessories are available and approved by Inspection department prior to installation.
- Ensure sufficient hand tools, power tools, ladder and scaffolding are available for installation.
- > Coordinate with other discipline and ensure site clearance is available to start the HVAC Activities.
- Arrange the sufficient manpower such as Supervisor, Foreman, Duct fitter, pipe fitter, Assistant duct and pipe fitter etc., and ensure all of them attended safety orientation and having proper PPE's prior start installation activities at site.
- Provide approved HVAC Shop drawing, MEP Co-ordination Drawing to site supervisor (or) Foreman and inform them to shift the required ducting and piping approved material from warehouse to site and arrange required material to avoid progress delay.
- > Prior to start HVAC activities notify to QC Personal for surveillance to ensure the quality work.
- Closely monitor site activities to ensure quality of work is in compliance with approved shop drawing and Specification and get daily progress report from site supervisor (or) foreman and update to project Manager.
- Preparing relevant documents to conduct inspection for completed installation activities and raise RFI to QC-Inspector (To ensure that any activity offered for inspection has an attachment of IFC drawing, method statement (if required), Inspection & Test Plan (ITP) followed by check list).
- Preparing the relevant documents to Conduct Testing inspection such as Duct light testing for Ducts and Hydro test for Above ground and Underground chilled water piping's, systems.
- Active involvement in weekly meetings with the Project management & QC Supervisor and manager to resolve the site related issues.
- Assist the Commissioning Team in Pre-commissioning & Commissioning stages of all HVAC Equipment's.
- Assist the Project Engineer during Preparation of final Test Reports, as built drawings, Operation & Maintenance manual and handing over the project to client.

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING

SUMMER TRAINING

COMPANY :DSL LOCOMOTIVE CHARBAGH LUCKNOW

> TECHNOLOGY :HIGH SPEED BOGIE OF DIESEL LOCOMOTIVE & ITS

MAINTENANCE

> DURATION : 4 WEEKS

INDUSTRIAL VISIT

- Company 1 :S.KUMAR industry lucknow on march 2016.
- Company 2 :UP NEDA lucknow on may 2016.
- Company 3 :BHARAT PUMP AND COMPRESSOR LIMITE(BPCL) on OCT 2016.
- Cold storage BKT lucknow on April 2017.

TECHNICALSKILLS

- Auto CAD
- MS Office
- ➤ MS Excel
- Drafting
- Heat load

Personal Skills:

- > Ability to achieve my goal.
- > Good & very Co- operative at team work.
- > Energetic and striving for Problem solving.
- Ability to analyses and derive logical inferences
- > Interested in updating the knowledge regularly
- > Punctuality and optimistic attitude towards Work.
- > Excellent Reporting & Management quality.
- > Good Management Skills verbal and written Communication skills
- > abilities and Hardworking and sincere

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : SHYAM KUMAR
DOB : 05-JULY-1996
Marital Status: Unmarried.
Language : English, Hindi.

I hereby declare that the above details provided are true to the best of my knowledge.

(SHYAM KUMAR)